# Parbhat Puri

## Software Developer

Kurukshetra - 136 128 - India https://parbhatpuri.com • https://github.com/parbhat

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Developer with an emphasis on performance, best practices and testing in order to create better applications. My experience primarily lies with the use of the Django (a Python web framework) as well as a wide range of other tools.

I like to involve in everything from the overall direction of a project, to design, user experience, and the actual implementation. I enjoy working on open source projects as it helps to give back to the community. I'm passionate about crafting great user experiences. And this influences all of my decisions as I work on a project.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## • Freelance Software Developer

June 2016 - Present

- Started as a part-time freelance developer and now working full-time as a freelancer.
- Worked on projects for startups, government, established companies and charities.
- Some of my clients are The motley fool (USA), Torchbox (UK) and Carpe (USA).
- Software Developer, ChrisDev Limited

June 2016 - November 2017

- The below position turned into Software Developer. Most of the work includes working on client projects with Python/Django, CSS/Sass, AngularJS and contributing to open source projects. Also, worked on the company startup called Flybottle which helps socially conscious organisations to raise money online. It was a part-time position as I like to explore Freelancing along the way.
- Full Stack Developer Intern, ChrisDev Limited

April 2015 - May 2016

- Remote position performed in the summer vacation and 4th year of my college.
- Designing and Developing client projects using technologies Python, Django, AngularJS, Sass, etc.
- Upgraded existing projects to the latest version of Django.
- Created RESTful APIs using Django Rest Framework.
- Created Test Suites which include unit tests and functional tests with Selenium. Increased test coverage of some projects to 100%.
- Started new open source projects and contributing to existing open source projects of the company.

## **OPEN SOURCE**

- Python Pedia: One stop for Python Programming resources. It's all about Python.
- Pelican Blue: Responsive theme for Pelican Static Site generator, powered by Python.
- Cookiecutter Django Foundation: Fork of Cookiecutter Django based on Zurb Foundation.
- Django Pandas: Tools for working with Pandas in Django projects.
- Django Pandas examples: Some examples of iPython/Jupyter Notebooks for django-pandas.
- Wagtail Cookiecutter Foundation: A Cookiecutter template for Wagtail using Zurb Foundation.
- Django Wagtail Feeds: Adds support for RSS and JSON Feeds to Wagtail CMS projects.
- Django Foundation formtags: Template tags for working with Foundation Forms in Django.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python backend development: Django, Flask, Wagtail (CMS)

Frontend development: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Vue, Foundation for sites, Bootstrap

Databases: MySql, PostgreSQL

**Operating System:** macOS, GNU/Linux **Version Control:** Git, mercurial

#### **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2016 B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

SHRI MATA VAISHNO DEVI UNIVERSITY, Jammu

CGPA: 7.53/10

2012 CBSE XII Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

PERCENTAGE: 89.8%

2010 CBSE X Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

CGPA: 9/10

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

December 2014 CS50x, Introduction to Computer Science

edX, Harvard University, Certificate ID - c7231f175e354755b8de46c98dc23fae

July 2014 Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms

NPTEL, IIT Madras, Roll No: NPTEL140300004517

October 2013 Networked Life

Coursera, University of Pennsylvania

July 2013 An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python

Coursera, Rice University

## **ACHIEVEMENTS & POSITIONS HELD**

- CBSE Merit Scholarship: Central Sector Scheme of Scholarship for College and University students (CSSS-2012).
- Speaker for Github Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2015. The Workshop covers git version control system(VCS) and git workflow to contribute to an Open Source project on github.
- Coordinated Software Freedom Day 2015 and was responsible to manage the overall event.
- Speaker for Python Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2014. The Workshop covers basics and importance of Python Programming language.
- Coordinated Software Freedom Day 2014 in my University.
- Initiated a Technical environment in the University by forming clubs like *Codechef campus chapter, PyClub* and organising various Workshops.

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

ADDRESS: Kurukshetra, 136 128, Haryana, India

PHONE: +91 9468315914 SKYPE: parbhat.puri

EMAIL: me@parbhatpuri.com
WEBSITE: https://parbhatpuri.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/parbhat

GITHUB: https://github.com/parbhat
TWITTER: https://twitter.com/parbhatpuri
SLIDES: http://slides.com/parbhat